<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ERMA7300 on Statistical Conditioning</title>
    <link>/tags/erma7300/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ERMA7300 on Statistical Conditioning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 William Murrah</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/erma7300/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Model Comparison,  and the General Linear Model</title>
      <link>/post/modeling-glm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modeling-glm/</guid>
      <description>In this post I present a brief overview of a model comparison approach to the general linear model. The goal is to establish a framework to understand basic statistical methods including \(t\) tests, analysis of variance, and linear regression. This framework and the example data are from Maxwell, Delaney, and Kelly (2018). Follow this link to find information on this textbook and the accompanying website. Both are excellent, but the text is somewhat advanced for those just learning statistical methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factorial Anova: Two-Way Between Subjects ANOVA</title>
      <link>/post/factorial-anova-two-way-between-subjects-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/factorial-anova-two-way-between-subjects-anova/</guid>
      <description>library(knitr) library(AMCP) library(car) ## Loading required package: carData library(pander) library(ztable) ## Welcome to package ztable ver 0.1.8 library(emmeans) library(tidyverse) ## ── Attaching packages ───────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse 1.2.1 ── ## ✔ ggplot2 2.2.1 ✔ purrr 0.2.4 ## ✔ tibble 1.4.2 ✔ dplyr 0.7.4 ## ✔ tidyr 0.8.0 ✔ stringr 1.3.0 ## ✔ readr 1.1.1 ✔ forcats 0.3.0 ## ── Conflicts ──────────────────────────────────────────── tidyverse_conflicts() ── ## ✖ dplyr::filter() masks stats::filter() ## ✖ dplyr::lag() masks stats::lag() ## ✖ dplyr::recode() masks car::recode() ## ✖ purrr::some() masks car::some() opts_chunk$set(echo = TRUE, comment = NULL, highlight = FALSE) options(ztable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Way ANOVA </title>
      <link>/post/one-way-anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/one-way-anova/</guid>
      <description>When comparing a continuous outcome between two groups, the \(t\) test is the basic test used. But, what do you do when you have more than two groups to compare? A foundational technique for this purpose is analysis of variance (ANOVA). This post is a conceptual overveiw of ANOVA, leading to example analyses aimed at developing intuitions about how ANOVA works. To get the most out of this post, you should work through a textbook chapter on one way ANOVA ahead of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon: How to use this website!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects Size Estimates</title>
      <link>/post/effects-size-estimates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/effects-size-estimates/</guid>
      <description>Cohen’s D Cohen’s D is the number of standard deviations an effect is shifted above or below the populations mean stated by the null hypothesis.
z test When we have known population parameters, we use them to calculate \[ d = \frac{\bar{X} - \mu}{\sigma} \] Note that \(\sigma\) is the standard deviation and NOT the standard error of the mean.
 One-sample t test \[ d = \frac{\bar{X} - \mu}{s} \]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variability</title>
      <link>/post/variability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/variability/</guid>
      <description>Important Notation Scientific notation, while often confusing and frustrating initially, is very useful in helping to convey complex ideas in a compact and precise manner. The table below contains scientific notations relevant to the previous tutorial on central tendency and this one on variability.
We will be using the following notation in this class:
  Symbol meaning    \(y\) Dependent Variable  \(x\) Independent Variable  \(N\) Population size  \(n\) Sample size  \(\Sigma\) Sum of  \(\mu\) Population mean  \(M\) sample mean (also often \(\bar{x}\))  \(M_w\) Weighted mean (or \(\bar{x}_w\) )  \(IQR\) Interquartile range  \(\sigma^2\) Population variance  \(s^2\) sample variance  \(\sigma\) Population standard deviation  \(s\) sample standard deviation     Range GRE scores for two classes with the same mean (151.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Data Into SPSS and R</title>
      <link>/post/getting-data-into-spss-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-data-into-spss-and-r/</guid>
      <description>The first step in analyzing data is often getting the data into your chosen software. In this tutorial, I demonstrate how to manually enter data into SPSS and R as well as how to import existing date from two common formats.
Manually Entering Data Let&amp;rsquo;s assume you had the following data on five students grades you wanted to enter into SPSS and R. You have 5 cases, in this example students, and two variables, the student&amp;rsquo;s name and their grade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ERMA 7300: Design and Analysis I</title>
      <link>/project/dai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dai/</guid>
      <description>Course Description Basic methods of descriptive and inferential analysis including t-tests, between and within subjects ANOVA, mixed ANOVAs, hierarchical designs and chi-square tests as they are utilized in educational research. Emphasis is placed on developing a solid foundation in statistical reasoning, including the assumptions, limitations, and common mistakes in using statistical methods.
Course Objectives Upon completion of this course, the student will be able to:
 explain the process of hypothesis testing and apply it to research problems identify different types of research designs and variables found in published articles describe the strengths and limitations of different research designs identify applications of a wide variety of statistical procedures solve educational research problems using statistical tests of significance make accurate interpretations of statistical findings use data analysis software (SPSS) to solve statistical problems review published research literature to examine the application of measurement, design, and analysis procedures prepare a written summary of data analysis results in APA format  Relevant Posts by Unit 0-Introduction 1-Visualizing and Describing Data Central Tendency</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Central Tendency</title>
      <link>/post/central-tendency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/central-tendency/</guid>
      <description>Important Notation Scientific notation, while often confusing and frustrating initially, is very useful in helping to convey complex ideas in a compact and precise manner. The table below contains scientific notations relevant to this tutorial on central tendency and the next on variability.
We will be using the following notation in this class:
  Symbol meaning    \(y\) Dependent Variable  \(x\) Independent Variable  \(N\) Population size  \(n\) Sample size  \(\Sigma\) Sum of  \(\mu\) Population mean  \(M\) sample mean (also often \(\bar{x}\))  \(M_w\) Weighted mean (or \(\bar{x}_w\) )  \(IQR\) Interquartile range  \(\sigma^2\) Population variance  \(s^2\) sample variance  \(\sigma\) Population standard deviation  \(s\) sample standard deviation     Mean Calculating the mean \[ \text{Population mean: } \\ \mu = \frac{\Sigma x}{N}\\ \]</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>