<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ERMA8340 on Statistical Conditioning</title>
    <link>/tags/erma8340/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ERMA8340 on Statistical Conditioning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 William Murrah</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/erma8340/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FIML in Lavaan: Descriptive Statistics</title>
      <link>/post/fiml-in-lavaan-descriptive-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fiml-in-lavaan-descriptive-statistics/</guid>
      <description>FIML for Missing Data in Lavaan Full information maximum likelihood (FIML) is a modern statistical technique for handling missing data. If you are not familiar with FIML, I would recommend the book entitled Applied Missing Data Analysis by Craig Enders. The book is both thorough and accessible, and a good place to start for those not familiar with the ins and outs of modern missing data techniques.
The purpose of the FIML in Lavaan series of posts and the related git repository is to take some of the examples related to FIML estimation within a regression framework from the Applied Missing Data website, and translate them into code for the R package lavaan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Model Comparison,  and the General Linear Model</title>
      <link>/post/modeling-glm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modeling-glm/</guid>
      <description>In this post I present a brief overview of a model comparison approach to the general linear model. The goal is to establish a framework to understand basic statistical methods including \(t\) tests, analysis of variance, and linear regression. This framework and the example data are from Maxwell, Delaney, and Kelly (2018). Follow this link to find information on this textbook and the accompanying website. Both are excellent, but the text is somewhat advanced for those just learning statistical methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>